[
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670914,
    "Question": "The Musi and Bhima are tributaries of the river ...............",
    "OP1": "Brahmaputra",
    "OP2": "Mahanadi",
    "OP3": "Krishna",
    "OP4": "Kaveri",
    "Answer": "3",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670919,
    "Question": "Sundari, a well known species of trees, is found in:",
    "OP1": "himalayan mountains",
    "OP2": "tropical deciduous forests",
    "OP3": "mangrove forests",
    "OP4": "tropical rainforests",
    "Answer": "3",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670927,
    "Question": "Which of the following is mined in the Badampahar mines of Odisha?",
    "OP1": "Dolomite",
    "OP2": "Azurite",
    "OP3": "Hematite",
    "OP4": "Bauxite",
    "Answer": "3",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670945,
    "Question": "Name the pass in Uttarakhand which is used by pilgrims to Kailash-Mansarovar Yatra.",
    "OP1": "Khardung La",
    "OP2": "Pensi La",
    "OP3": "Banihal Pass",
    "OP4": "Lipu Lekh",
    "Answer": "4",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670950,
    "Question": "Which of the following Biosphere Reserves was the first to be established by the Government of India?",
    "OP1": "Sundarbans Biosphere Reserve",
    "OP2": "Nilgiri Biosphere Reserve",
    "OP3": "Gulf of Mannar Biosphere Reserve",
    "OP4": "Nanda Devi Biosphere Reserve",
    "Answer": "2",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670964,
    "Question": "Baglihar Dam is constructed on which river?",
    "OP1": "Chenab",
    "OP2": "Sutlej",
    "OP3": "Indus",
    "OP4": "Ravi",
    "Answer": "1",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670969,
    "Question": "In which of the following states, is the Nanda Devi peak located?",
    "OP1": "Jammu and Kashmir",
    "OP2": "Sikkim",
    "OP3": "Assam",
    "OP4": "Uttarakhand",
    "Answer": "4",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670976,
    "Question": "‘Mithun’, a cattle breed is found in ______.",
    "OP1": "Tamilnadu",
    "OP2": "Arunachal Pradesh",
    "OP3": "Maharashtra",
    "OP4": "Kerala",
    "Answer": "2",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670982,
    "Question": "________, which connects Sikkim with Tibet, was closed after the Chinese aggression on India in 1962 but was reopened in 2006 as the governments of the two countries decided to enhance their trade through land routes.",
    "OP1": "Lanak La",
    "OP2": "Imis La",
    "OP3": "Pensi La",
    "OP4": "Nathu La",
    "Answer": "4",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "noteId": 1739601670984,
    "Question": "Where is the Bandipur National Park located?",
    "OP1": "Gujarat",
    "OP2": "Sikkim",
    "OP3": "Karnataka",
    "OP4": "Kerala",
    "Answer": "3",
    "Extra": "",
    "tags": [
      "Geography",
      "GK",
      "Prelims-4"
    ]
  }
]